Edward R. Murrow Papers MS025
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Audiotapes and other media, 1939 -- 1974; MS025.005; 56.1 Linear Feet; 19 Audiovisual Object(s); 592 Digital Object(s)
  - This I Believe (10" Audiotape Reels), 1951 -- 1954; MS025.005.004; 16 Audiovisual Object(s); 587 Digital Object(s)
    - This I Believe, XTV21530, MS025.005.004.012.00003 (Reel data_value_missing_42aff8a74509e2f508f945e00e73485c)
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.012.00003.00004; Penfield, Wilder (Reel data_value_missing_42aff8a74509e2f508f945e00e73485c)
        War stories; Life; God; Purpose; Faith; Liberty; Science; Immaterialism; audio tape; McGill University; Montreal Neurological Institute
      - This I Believe, MS025.005.004.012.00003.00005; Wilson, Claire D. (Reel data_value_missing_42aff8a74509e2f508f945e00e73485c)
        Claire Wilson, President of Vernon Oil and Gas Company, talks about his optimism and faith, his belief in the responsibility of the individual to improve themselves for thegood of society, altruism, and the impact of meditation and trips to the mountains on his serenity and peace of mind.
        Self-culture; Change; Optimism; Humanity; Faith; Fortitude; Individualism; Altruism; Aging; Meditation; audio tape
    - This I Believe, XTV21531, MS025.005.004.012.00004 (Reel data_value_missing_42aff8a74509e2f508f945e00e73485c)
    - This I Believe, XTV21532, MS025.005.004.012.00005 (Reel data_value_missing_42aff8a74509e2f508f945e00e73485c)
      10" Reel. Job#-. "805931 Job 6578" written on reel.
      - Freedom and a Piece of String, MS025.005.004.012.00005.00001; Read, Conyers (Reel data_value_missing_42aff8a74509e2f508f945e00e73485c)
        Conyers Read enumerates some of his beliefs, such as the ability to concern one's self only with that which one can control; the importance of creative abilities and freedom of thought; and standards of right and wrong. Audio also includes an advertisement for a "This I Believe" book.
        Liberty; Racism; Equality; Freedom; Creative ability; Faith; Ethics; Immortality; audio tape; University of Pennsylvania; American Historical Association
      - Nietzsche Stands Condemned, MS025.005.004.012.00005.00002; Allen, Florence Ellinwood (Reel data_value_missing_42aff8a74509e2f508f945e00e73485c)
        Florence Allen, Circuit Judge of the United States Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit, explains her worry over the "deterioration of the human spirit" and her belief that faith and intelligence and the fair application of law may restore the human spirit and through law create a peacful planet. Audio includes an advertisement for "This I Believe" book.
        Faith; Law; Ethics; War; Peace; Civil rights; Liberty; audio tape; United States. Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit.
    - This I Believe and Promo, XTV21597 and XTV21598, MS025.005.004.012.00006 (Reel data_value_missing_42aff8a74509e2f508f945e00e73485c)
      10" Reel. Job#-. Reel is empty. "51" written on reel cover.
    - This I Believe, XTV16106, 1951-11-26 -- 1952-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00001 (Reel 13)
      10" Reel. Job#113067
      - The Human Equation, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00001.00001; Cobbs, Susan Parker (Reel 13)
        Swarthmore College classicist Susan Parker Cobbs believes, as Socrates did, that the unexamined life is not worth living. Cobbs says all people have goodness within them, which can be expressed where there is freedom, faith and truth.
        Introspection; Self-Consciousness (Awareness); Happiness; Philosophy; Liberty; Belief; Truth; Humanism; Young adults; Human beings; Compassion; Love; audio tape; Swarthmore College
      - This I Believe, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00001.00002; Kelly, John B. (Reel 13)
        John Kelly tells the story of his disqualification from the Diamond Sculls rowing competition for having apprenticed as a bricklayer and the resulting hope to meet Beresford, the Diamond Sculls champion, in the Olympics to compete against him for the Gold Medal. Kelly concludes that he believes his failures are the most important memories he holds.
        Rowing; Olympics; Prejudice; Struggle; Prayer; Faith; Competition; Purpose; Failure (Psychology); audio tape; John B. Kelly, Inc.
      - The World's Greatest Force, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00001.00003; Schary, Dore (Reel 13)
        Dore Schary lists some of the beliefs he has acquired over the course of his life; the importance of family, equality of people, respect for law, democracy, patriotism, and concludes by describing the importance of wisdom to the past, present and future of the human race.
        Religion; Law; Immigrants; Patriotism; Democracy; Family; Individualism; Prejudice; Optimism; Wisdom; audio tape; Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer
      - If I Were a Dictator, 1952-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00001.00004; Reynolds, Quentin James (Reel 13)
        Quentin Reynolds explains why he would first burn the Bible if he were a dictator: the Bible is the source of democracy and its stories tell of the power of individuality and non-conformity which make a dictatorship impossible, according to Reynolds.
        Bible; Democracy; Individualism; Jesus Christ; Dictatorship; David, King of Israel; Goliath (Biblical Giant); audio tape
    - This I Believe, XTV16109, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00002 (Reel 13)
      10" Reel. Job# 113067. [side includes small white sticker with black cross, meaning unknown]
      - This I Believe, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00002.00001; Blake, Harry J. (Reel 13)
        Harry Blake describes a conversation with his sons in which they discuss the need for faith, hope, and charity to attain a succesful and happy life.
        Family; Life; Faith; Hope; Charity; Success; Happiness; audio tape; Blake and Company; Boston Chamber of Commerce
      - A Reporter Quotes His Sources, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00002.00002; Shirer, William L. (William Lawrence) (Reel 13)
        While reporting from Germany during Nazi rule, radio commentator William L. Shirer learned the value of tolerance and freedom and was inspired by people's ability to retain their faith and will to live in the face of attrocities. Shirer believes that mans resilience, especially during times of war, comes from having a rich inner life of reflection and contemplation.
        Dictatorship; War; Perseverance; Humanity; Human beings; Relativity; Self-Consciousness (Awareness); Dignity; World War, 1939-1945; audio tape; CBS Network
      - Guarding the Gift of Freedom, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00002.00003; Clay, Lucius D. (Lucius DuBignon) (Reel 13)
        Lucius D. Clay describes being inspired by the German people's desire for democracy following World War II and believes that all people want peace and liberty and also believes freedom is a privilege given by God, and one that must be carefully guarded by all citizens and he calls upon Americans to make this country one that provides equal opportunities for all.
        World War, 1939-1945; Berlin (Germany); Democracy; Honesty; Liberty; Optimism; Toleration; Responsibility; Cooperation; Progress; Citizenship; audio tape; United States Army; Berlin Airlift
      - This I Believe, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00002.00004; Bennett, Charles E. (Reel 13)
        Charles Bennett explains the importance of loyalty in Congress and in combat and also believes that individuals must repent for one's sins and develop strong faith to make the world a peaceful place.
        Loyalty; Friendship; Love; God; Good and evil; Repentance; Sin; Religious life; Faith; Individualism; audio tape; United States House of Representatives
    - This I Believe, XTV16110, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00003 (Reel 13)
      10" Reel. Job# 113067
      - The Hole in the Enemy's Armor, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00003.00001; Hoskins, Lewis M. (Reel 13)
        Lewis Hoskins recalls a time when he was taken prisoner by a chinese soldier while providing humanitarian aid and his ability to find a common humanity and brotherliness with his captor that disarmed the fear and violence of the situation.
        Humanitarianism; War; Brotherliness; Fear; Friendship; Kindness; Family; Society of Friends; Quakers; Humanity; audio tape; American Friends Service Committee
      - Spiritual Handholds on Life, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00003.00002; Fagg, Fred D. (Fred Dow) (Reel 13)
        Fred Fagg recalls a moment when his life was saved by a handhold at the edge of a cliff and uses this story to explain the importance of his own "spiritual handholds."
        Danger; Fear; Individualism; Faith; Security; audio tape; University of Southern California
      - Roll Away the Stone, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00003.00003; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker) (Reel 13)
        Writer Pearl S. Buck finds her faith in humanity to be stronger than ever, shares her affinity for life, and believes that cooperation can solve the worlds problems.
        Humanitarianism; Progress; Human beings; Humanity; Optimism; Good and evil; Cooperation; Happiness; Liberty; Security; audio tape; Nobel Prize
    - This I Believe, XTV16111, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00004 (Reel 13)
      10" Reel. Job# 113067 [side of original box includes small white sticker with black cross, meaning unknown
      - My Father's Evening Star, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00004.00001; Douglas, William O. (William Orville) (Reel 13)
        Christianity; Death; Faith; Liberty; Acquisitiveness; Spirituality; Self-determination, national; Christianity; audio tape; United States Supreme Court
      - A Straight Wall Is Hard to Build, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00004.00002; Crandall, Lou R. (Reel 13)
        Lou Crandall uses the analogy of construction to describe his belief that young people are foundations upon which a strong, straight character must be built, and looks to Biblical characters for examples of steadfast integrity.
        Analogy; Character; Personality Development; Young adults; Excellence-Religious aspects; Progress; audio tape; George A. Fuller Construction Company
      - The Road of Sanity and Morality, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00004.00003; Evans, Harold (Reel 13)
        Harold Evans recalls his relationship with Count Bernadotte who was assasinated while a Mediator on a U.N. peace keeping effort, and compares him with President Abraham Lincoln as two men with conviction, faith and integrity and examples of the type of individuals people can look up to to create prosperity and peace in the world for everyone.
        Lincoln, Abraham 1809-1865; Bernadotte, Folke, 1895-1948; Friendship; Mentoring; Religion; Religious life; Faith; Courage; Gratitude; Integrity; Peace; Society of Friends; audio tape; United Nations
      - The Thread of Permanence, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00004.00004; Zorach, William (Reel 13)
        William Zorach believes that people have had their faith strained and that it is important to get in touch with one's creative ability to communcate and define one's feelings in order to progress towards a world of happiness and prosperity.
        Christianity; Golden rule; Good and evil; Fear; Hope; Faith; Christianity; audio tape; Art Students League
    - This I Believe, XTV16112, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00005 (Reel 13)
      10" Reel. Job# 113068 [side includes small white sticker with black cross, meaning unknown] [MAJOR RESTORATION NEEDED]
      - This I Believe, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00005.00001; Sharples, Laurence P. (Laurence Price) (Reel 13)
        Laurence Sharples describes the essential beliefs he tries to live by; keep active and busy, educate his heart and have empathy, remain honest, and create something positive to leave behind.
        Altruism; Generosity; Purpose; Integrity; Honesty; Work; Persistence; Immortality; audio tape; Aircraft Owners and Pilots Association
      - This I Believe, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00005.00002; Savage, Susan (Reel 13)
        Belief change; Character; Death; Faith; Fortitude; Love; Perserverance; Self-Consciousness (Awareness); Uncertainty-Religious aspects; audio tape; Bryn Mawr
      - This I Believe, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00005.00003; Deustch, Monroe E. (Reel 13)
        Monroe Deustch expresses his belief that the sentiment of brotherhood between people could solve many of the world's problems and also expresses his belief that there is a greater power in the world that has created the Universe and that this power is immortal just as the spirit of people is immortal as well.
        Immortality; Brotherliness; Democracy; Individualism; Equality; Peace; Religions; Immaterialism; God; Human beings; audio tape; University of California
    - This I Believe, XTV16114, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00006 (Reel 13)
      10" Reel. Job# 113068
      - A Ball to Roll Around, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00006.00001; Allman, Robert G. (Reel 13)
        Robert Allman explains why losing his sight endowed him with an appreciation for life and how he learned to believe in himself and adapt and adjust to reality.
        Progress; Introspection; Human beings; Humanity; Philosophy; Good and evil; Individualism; audio tape; National Blind Golfers Association
      - Give Part of Yourself Away, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00006.00002; Taylor, Harold (Reel 13)
        Harold Taylor expresses his beliefe in the essential goodness of people and their natures and describes his philosophy that that, quality of life and faith in the future is a consequence of developing this goodness to live in harmony with other people.
        Charity; Honesty; Loyalty; Virtues; Values; audio tape; Sarah Lawrence College
      - Walk Clean Around the Hill, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00006.00003; Zanuck, Darryl Francis (Reel 13)
        Daryl Zanuck explains that the virtues he learned in his boyhood in Nebraska, charity and loyalty, are still the fundamental virtues that are most important in his life.
        Charity; Honesty; Loyalty; Virtues; Values; audio tape; Twentieth Century Fox
      - The Job of Citizenship, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00006.00004; Earle, Genevieve B. (Reel 13)
        Genevieve B. Earle remembers the surprise of seeing poverty as a child and how she developed a belief in the benefits of a strong government to promote laws and provide for its citizens although she says that can only happen when the people are engaged as active, equal partners in the work of a city.
        Social service; Citizenship; Poverty; Municipal government; Social justice; Progress; audio tape; New York City Council; League of Women Voters
    - This I Believe, XTV16115, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00007 (Reel 13)
      - This I Believe, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00007.00001; Borton, Elon G. (Reel 13)
        Elon Borton envies his fathers unwavering faith in God and explains his own evolving faith in God; that He has a plan and a purpose for everyone.
        God; God-knowableness; Faith; Struggle; Life; Nature; Good and evil; Equality; Respect for Persons; Freedom; audio tape; Advertizing Federation of America
      - Doing the Simple Tasks, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00007.00002; Jones, Susie Williams (Reel 13)
        Susie Jones believes spiritual fulfillment comes from attending to the mundane chores of daily life and describes her belief in the fundamental goodness of people her desrie to be one with God.
        Mothers; Housekeeping; Homemakers; Responsibility; Work; Kindness; Good and evil; Human beings; Struggle; Progress; audio tape; Bennett College (Greensboro, N.C.)
      - This I Believe, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00007.00003; Schauffler, Bennet F. (Reel 13)
        Bennet Schauffler talks about the importance of keeping active in order to find happiness, that if one enjoys what one is doing and works at it one has no time, or inclination, to argue or fight with others. boredom and inactivity have led people to conflict and materialistic greed.
        Acquisitiveness; Work; Happiness; Humanity; Understanding; Human beings; Empathy; audio tape; National Labor Relations Board
    - This I Believe, XTV16116, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00008 (Reel 13)
      - This I Believe, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00008.00001; Trilling, Louis R. (Reel 13)
        Louis Trilling talks about how beliefs change, particularly as one changes, and what is important is that one does have beliefs to follow and that for one to be happy and content one should believe in something outside of oneself.
        Belief change; Aging; Questioning; Self-confidence; Human beings; Mentoring; Individualism; Failure; Courage; audio tape; City College of New York
      - This I Believe, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00008.00002; Gopolakrishnan, R. (Reel 13)
        R.Gopolakrishnan describes his awareness, upon coming to America, that the beliefs and dreams of Americans are the same as those of the people of India and that the desire for peace, liberty, brotherhood and cooperation are not limited by national borders.
        United States; Democracy; Humanity; Brotherliness; Progress; Peace; Cooperation; audio tape; Harvard University
    - This I Believe, XTV16117, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00009 (Reel 13)
      10" Reel. Job#113068
      - Don't Step Out of Character, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00009.00001; Sale, Virginia (Reel 13)
        Virginia Sale believes that to have a succesful and happy life it is important to do good for others in all things and to do this she tries to remember to act always as one of God's children.
        Death; War; Struggle; Prayer; Religious life; Faith; Happiness; Success; Purpose; audio tape
      - This I Believe, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00009.00002; Evans, Bob (Reel 13)
        Bob Evans explains his belief in the individual and the individual's responsibility to oneself, to one's community, and to one's God, emphasizing the importance of equality, self respect and the Ten Commandments.
        Good and evil; Dignity; Human rights; Responsibility; self-respect; Equality; Work; Individualism; Religious life; Ten commandments; audio tape; University of Pennsylvania
      - A Lesson Learned at Midnight, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00009.00003; Du Pont, James Q. (James Quinn) (Reel 13)
        James Du Pont explains his belief that life is difficult but people are strong, although complicated by being both good and bad, and to be good one must be humble, compassionate and have faith.
        Struggle; Fortitude; Good and evil; Humanity; Introspection; Compassion; Humility; Fate; audio tape; Du Pont Company; Manhattan Project
    - This I Believe, XTV16118, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00010 (Reel 13)
      - This I Believe, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00010.00001; Smith, Bradford (Reel 13)
        Bradford Smith describes his fascination with the universe and its creation and the importance of creativity in life, bith in general and in a person's life, and that one must develop this creativity through social connections, democracy and love.
        Nature; Life; Purpose; Creative ability; Happiness; Social Networks; Cooperation; Democracy; Love; audio tape; Guggenheim Fellow
      - You Have to Water the Plant, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00010.00002; Stowe, Leland (Reel 13)
        Leland Stowe talks about his experiences around the world meeting different people and the similarities he saw and how his expereinces convinced him that everyone should try to undestand other people and act with comapsiion and empathy.
        Human beings; Compassion; Empathy; Understanding; Toleration; Freedom; Humanity; Equality; Respect for Persons; Friendship; audio tape; Pulitzer Prize
    - This I Believe, XTV16119, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00011 (Reel 13)
      - This I Believe, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00011.00001; Totton, Frank M. (Reel 13)
        Frank Totton describes the meaning he finds in life as a result of his religious faith and belief that God works through man which encourages and enables him to support and aid others.
        Struggle; Deafblind women; Compassion; Meaning; Faith; Progress; God; Christianity; Jesus Christ; Charity; Presbyterianism; audio tape; Chase National Bank; United Negro College Fund; New York State YMCA
      - The Law of Shared Investment, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00011.00002; Overstreet, Bonaro W. (Wilkinson) (Reel 13)
        Bonaro Overstreet talks about her doubt and her one certain belief, that we must all act towards one another with good will and kindness because people are intimately connected and the notion of individuality is a misperception.
        Kindness; Cooperation; Golden rule; Social Networks; Human beings; Philosophy; Equality; Toleration; audio tape
      - This I Believe, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00011.00003; Underhill, Irvin Windfield (Reel 13)
        Reverend Irvin Underhill believes that good things can come out of adversity when one keeps faith and he recalls an experience in Africa in which fear and danger led him to peace and tranquility.
        Poverty; Struggle; Religious life; Blindness; Faith; Missionary stories; Fear; Prayer; Christianity; Africa; Presbyterianism; audio tape; England's Royal Geographic Society; University of Pennsylvania; Princeton Theological Seminary
      - This I Believe, 1951-11-26; MS025.005.004.013.00011.00004; Hottel, Althea K. (Krantz) (Reel 13)
        Althea Hottel remembers an influential poem and advice from her grandmother and how these things have shaped her and impacted her experience in life and religion.
        Gratitude; Science; Religion; Equality; Peace; Human beings; Humanity; Christianity; audio tape; University of Pennsylvania
    - This I Believe, XTV16155, 1951-12-07; MS025.005.004.013.00012 (Reel 13)
      - Dictators Cannot Kill It, 1951-12-07; MS025.005.004.013.00012.00001; Stassen, Harold Edward (Reel 13)
        Harold Stassen describes Albert Schweitzer's life and his philosophy of "reverance for life," and from this explains why people yearn for freedom and dictatorships can never stop this yearning.
        Schweitzer, Albert, 1875-1965; Life; Faith; Human beings; Dictatorship; audio tape; University of Pennsylvania
      - This I Believe, 1951-12-07; MS025.005.004.013.00012.00002; Eristoff, Anne (Reel 13)
        Anne Eristoff does not believe the concept of Hell should be a motivating factor for good behavior but rather believes that incentive should come from wanting to be a part of the natural harmony of the world through goodness, truth and beauty.
        God-knowableness; Immaterialism; Ethics; Kindness; Truth; Beauty; Nature; Compassion; Harmony; Science; Religion; audio tape; Bryn Mawr College
      - This I Believe, 1951-12-07; MS025.005.004.013.00012.00003; Lukas, Edwin J. (Jay) (Reel 13)
        Edwin Lukas speaks about the importance of tolerance and respect for other people, cultures and races and the negative impact prejudice can have on an individual and a community.
        Change; Respect for Persons; Toleration; Prejudice; Equality; Racism; Dignity; audio tape; American Jewish Committee
      - This I Believe, 1951-12-07; MS025.005.004.013.00012.00004; Richie, David S. (Reel 13)
        David Richie mentions a social experiment he tried in which he behaved selfishly one week and selflessly the following, what he discovered is that he felt better when acting selflessly and he believes now that good deeds can only be accomplished through good means.
        Altruism; Kindness; Humanitarianism; Social Work; Equality; Brotherliness; Friendship; audio tape; Friends Social Order Committee
    - This I Believe, XTV16159, 1951-12-07; MS025.005.004.014.00001 (Reel 14)
      10" Reel. Job# 113132 [on a side of box, small white sticker with black inverted T, meaning unknown
      - This I Believe, 1951-12-07; MS025.005.004.014.00001.00001; Donaldson, Anne Talbot (Reel 14)